hello
my name is grian and welcome back to
another episode of hermitcraft as you
can see ow
i have done a lot of excavating you
might not even be able to work out where
i am well this all used to be underwater
and this is my double glazed coral reef
and i'm really surprised at how well you
can see through this it looks absolutely
brilliant it's very messy on the inside
that's where it used to be along there
the floor used to be there
if we go outside which the only way out
at the moment is to fly but i'm gonna
fix that a bit later on you can see that
not a lot has changed to be honest from
this angle it's mainly this bottom layer
which now encompasses this whole thing
and i'm just really happy with how
everything's going it's almost time to
work on the final layer of this and i
think i have a pretty good idea once
that final layer is done i can then
start kitting out what i want to put in
each one of these layers i have some
pretty cool ideas but before we get into
working on the base a bit more i need to
go over to the shopping district
what did i do to deserve that
oh he's come
oh my goodness it is pandemonium right
now oh my goodness look how many
skeleton horses jack skelebones are back
oh this is oh this is madness
there's a thunderstorm going on and it
is it's just all going down
carbon skara here at least i'm gonna get
my skeleton back
oh no this is bad at least you could do
this
you could charge them with great speed
what just happened
chaos
uh i want me those skelebone horses
yeah i want one as well there's three
over here there's one behind scott has
already killed two and i don't think i
can ever forgive him
those were vicious creatures that were
out to kill me and i don't regret a
minute but i also want one myself i'm
gonna sleep
i'm gonna fly over no because then we
can't fly forever i've even showed it
off yet look how you could go for you
could go infinitely and you can go
really fast
yeah look at the distance i'm covering
here
you can't see this you can't sleep
through this
see cub
yeah it's pretty great it's pretty great
you don't have to use any rockets
oh oh oh i hit false's shop
dang it
oh dude i'm in the mining district
oh thanks the skeleton is dying on its
own this one's my horse
this is my horse you are mine oh no no
no no
[Laughter]
this has gone very well guys this has
gone very well i went the same why am i
such an idiot that skeleton suffocated
in a wall so i hopped on the same horse
that killed the ski oh my god hey guys i
have an idea maybe we should sleep
yeah
there we go
i am such a fool i'm such an
unbelievable fool i can't believe i did
that okay guys since we are all in this
pandemonium together
should we sell the leftover horses we
keep the ones for us and we sell the
leftovers yep
everyone wants to be like a undead
submarine in the water you got a
skeleton horse head man
nice wow now that's rare because they're
they're a rare drop on any mob
all right i'm going to claim this gala
bone horse
for me
revived
once more so how do you kill the uh the
skeleton on the horse
because i killed the horse every time
yeah i know great accuracy watch this
you ready oh
oh no he fires back scar do something
scott oh i don't have any i don't have
any weapons oh i hit the oh we need club
for this oh i did it
oh my god i i need that head hold on
hold on hold on here's your trident
oh i thought you were gonna give me the
scope
that's easily the best okay okay
okay here you go here we go
those are mine
come on man oh
[Music]
come on man you can make something with
all that we'll we'll see we'll see we'll
see
oh nicole
who hit the horse oh no oh
my god my bad
i swear there was like eight spawned did
we get no there's one over here we
all right
i can snipe from a distance i'm pretty
good can i use the trident maybe
oh look at that first time one down
oh
come on i'll just stand it no don't
throw it don't scar don't you dare
just leave let him do it
there we go
there we go all right three more
he threw his trine just as i hit it so
he's tried and killed the skeleton and
then my bow oh
yeah it was sad there were tears but
we're over it now we got three to sell
20 diamonds a piece what do you think
[Music]
we're becoming skelebone submarines
right
yep let's do it let's go do it
dive dive down wait what in the world he
kicked me off again no he's running he
doesn't want to go in the water
none of us have this problem scar
jeez man get back here man are you
pressing sh you're pressing shift to go
down in the water aren't you
how else do you supposed to go down you
just let me sink because that's you
dismantle dismounting here
there's a ravine here
oh that's fancy that's a problem though
if you go down there's no coming up
skye's already committed
i'm going back no
[Music]
give me that skull and i'll help you up
[Laughter]
i don't know how to jump i'll make you a
way
you're kidding me right
why did my guy just my horse just
decided to leave
why did my horse decide to go in the
same room honestly like i just got off
for a second i turn around and he's like
knee deep in there there we go i'm out
okay
okay see green green has made it
scary has lost dead sea though
it's
this thing's gone way wrong here yeah
you probably need to reload i see you i
see you right here on the face what
scott what
phantom scar
you saw that too you saw that too we're
not going crazy right yeah very cool i'm
here guys
that was a real scar that was weird
how are we gonna make money
let's make a stable for these guys we're
gonna sell the excess horses right and
we've got a pretty decent spot picked
out so we got all our horses here and
we're gonna make a little stable here
and we're not gonna spend too much time
on it because as soon as these horses
are gone that's it
what do you reckon how much do we sell
these for i'm feeding about 32 because
you know you just cut a stack of
diamonds you just cut that thing off
it's perfect 32. you have a big stack
you just cut it up i say 32. yeah let's
see if they sell also well what if we
also
give them really like punny names so
that they sell better so like people can
peruse which pun they think is the best
yeah
yeah that's a good idea good idea have
you got any pods
if we could put pods on it
wait actually it doesn't really make
sense because they don't well they're
eating why do they even eat their
skeleton horses i mean these are the
questions we need to keep asking jeb why
can they suffocate
why do they eat they've got they've got
none of these functions
well that's the roof kind of done i need
to put a bit more on this side and then
i think we'll be done
looks like we're all finished
shall i explain the deal then how this
is all going to pan out
we've got indeed we've got a little
wager so we managed to secure three
horses we're going to take three of ours
home i've decided to call mine
jack skelebone named after the original
jack skelebone that perished may he
forever rest in pieces
and
tragic you've decided
concord cavalry of course calling the
cavalry scott what have you even even
named yours
no my personal horse does not have a
name i need suggestions because i outdid
myself with my
horse for sale i feel like i used up all
my naming uh points so the other three
we've decided that we're gonna have a
little wager we're gonna try and sell
all of these and they cost 32 diamonds i
think it's a little bit high but they
say it's fine so
whatever and each of them have a name
that we have given them
uh i won't say who who named what or
maybe we should
maybe we shouldn't stand next to the
horses we choose
yeah i think it's a dead giveaway
uh yeah i'll be getting this one over
here
yeah all right
i named my napoleon bonaparte
and
so
we decided whoever
has whoever sells the first horse
because realistically they're going to
look at all of the puns first right and
they're going to make their decision
based on the pun
there's a little secret chest behind
here that has the skeleton head horse
that everybody wants plus three diamonds
so there's there's real reason to want
to win this
so the pun battle is on
and whoever sells the first horse claims
the prize all right
well we'll leave it at that then boys
let's
let's call it quits oh i'm so happy that
i have a horse back i was so devastated
the first time
please don't kill it this time we'll
have to get rand to watch you the hermit
environmental
agency of documentary old films
i
promise to look after this one i'm not
gonna make the same mistake i made last
time all right safe travels safe travel
see you dudes
is anybody getting a bit of deja vu
let's bring him back and now we know
exactly how to handle
this so let's get him back to the base
the only way we know how
underwater skelebone machine
now that we know he's not gonna drown we
don't have to worry so much hey look
there's there's even the entrance that i
made before
okay we're not gonna mess this up oh you
can see the reef room in here not as
well for as the inside but it still
looks decent still gotta wait for me to
sink now
if i'm not much mistaken
i'm just gonna i'm just gonna do this
the safe way i'm not even gonna be i'm
not even gonna pretend like
i know what i'm doing i'm not gonna
bring them anywhere near those bubbles
we're gonna go up the normal
safe way come along jack scalabone
that's where your brother died
we're not gonna go there
we're gonna go up the stairway to heaven
ah we made it
oh it's it's beautiful it's beautiful
oh we can
well now that i've actually got him here
there's not a lot i can do with him but
it's brilliant he's he's my eternal
friend he's gonna roam around here
forever and we're gonna be best friends
so the first thing that i need to do is
work out how to get up and down and i
think i've done that with a couple of
tubes with a water elevator i think
that's by far going to be the easiest
way
and i think we need to clear this out
now the reason i've only done just over
half is because i've got a farm to take
care of here
i don't really want to move it just yet
although having said that
i have got a huge amount of carrots and
potatoes
yeah i think we can probably move this
this should keep me going for a really
long time so this was only temporary we
can move it
we can remove it for now i think
oh
oh that was a mistake oh that was oh
that was a silly now all my torches are
gone
and we
are pretty much clean
now i'm gonna i'm not gonna lie to you
guys this is probably the most dull
thing i've ever done in minecraft ever
because what it to clear this out this
used to be all underwater the the water
line is actually out here so all of this
is strictly speaking underwater
and to get rid of it what you have to do
is make these little pools of sand so
you gotta make a three by three made out
of sand
and that means placing sand over and
over again to create these walls all the
way up the side like so when you've done
that you then need to remove this and
you've got some water in the middle
then you hop in with the sponge
and you start draining it out
once you've cleared it of water you then
got to take your torches
and get rid of all the sand that you
just created collect it all up
and then you do the same all over again
so as you can tell
clearing out this area took me a really
long time and i've still got a little
bit left to do but once that's done this
area is going to make a really cool like
interior aquarium type thing and also
what i've done is i've created a
semi-automatic
concrete dispenser so this is how i'm
gonna get white concrete faster so i've
made a temporary one there i used a cub
fans tutorial so that's pretty cool
and now i'm just working on a way to get
up and down from here but i also want to
make it so that it's not too intrusive i
want it to kind of blend in which is why
it's all made of glass at the moment the
only way in and out of this aquarium at
the moment is through this little hole
uh but i think
since this is here permanently
i'm gonna add paul in here and i'm gonna
add codswallop in here so that they're
free to float about forever
uh brilliant so only some of these are
named like this guy here he's not named
he's not named at all he's just a salmon
but if you go over here you'll see two
tropical fish now tropical fish do not
spawn in this biome so you can tell that
i went out of my way to get these guys
and they are called
fish and i am a fish
so what i'm gonna do here is put in some
water take some kelp go all the way down
and we need to make these all source
blocks and the easiest way to do that is
with kelp once it's all full we can then
go down the bottom and remove the bottom
lock and it should create the bubbles we
need to get up
excellent and there we have our first
bubble column up
and the other side remove these and we
have the right uh
that's not enough
that's not enough might want to put that
one block up then we have a double
column system i could have made this all
redstone but
i don't know that the two columns there
seems to work i probably should do this
on all four of these entrances but since
this is all a work in progress i'm just
gonna stick to this one for now this is
really starting to look like a villain's
secret layer isn't it this doesn't look
like the hero's base
excellent this works perfectly oh jack
skelebone we can wander around our
villainous base together forever mumbo
was asking for some cobbles so broham to
the rescue with two shulker boxes full
of cobble hey mumbo
here he is he hasn't even noticed me yet
hello oh hello
there we go two shulker boxes full of
cobblestone oh no no need you can you
can pay me in bro points later
i'm getting so good at flying out of his
base now it's so satisfying this looks
really cool i can't wait to see this bit
complete
now
i don't know whether he's gonna keep
these pixel arts around his face i
personally
wouldn't but they are so high quality
maybe he'll just keep them around until
they're in the way delivering cobble and
making water elevators isn't what i
planned on doing today at all i got very
much distracted by the pandemonium
lightning thing that went on and i got
even more distracted by the fact that we
got skeleton horses it's good to have
you backs jack skelebone
what we're actually gonna do today is
get ourselves a beacon i went and
collected three wither skulls i had very
bad luck on my first try trying to get
these it took three hours and i got none
and then i went and used the farm and i
got three skulls in 20 minutes so i
guess that's just the way it crumbles
actually i'm gonna need some soul sand
ah i moved my nether portal i bet it's
not linked up properly anymore
oh dear
what
what the heck
it's definitely not linked up anymore
what the heck is born one in the middle
of the air oh well i guess that's free
obsidian but
i need to link this up better because
that's not the right place what we're
gonna do is we're gonna go down and
we're gonna make ourselves a little
cavern at bedrock to take care of this
oh what do you know hello diamonds
i'll be honest i have no idea what i'm
doing i'm just gonna have to spawn it
and give it a go i think i'm kind of
scared i don't really want to do this
but i got to i'm sure if i die someone
will help me right
[Music]
there we go
bows at the reddies boys
those that they're ready
it's terrifying
where is he
oh he's up there
ah
i need to just keep going for him
he's got he's he's encroaching on me
come on there we go come on
back it up
we're getting him we're getting there
keep going
and last one come on
there we go oh my goodness
that wasn't enjoyable
that wasn't enjoyable at all but i'm
quite proud of myself for doing it first
time didn't need any help or anything
i was so confident in fact i did it with
10 diamonds on me
and look at all this free cobble wait a
minute i got a i got to wither play
ahead
this is going to be rare right unless
everyone gets them in which case oops
but i haven't seen anyone with this this
is awesome i am green
king of the wither
and here we go
we need three obsidian
glass
the never star
we got a beacon i think i need to spend
a little time
figuring out all this junk in my base
because
there is so much rubbish here
now i actually went and salvaged all of
the uh blocks of iron that were on top
of the pickle jar because
yeah i realized that that was a stupid
thing and now i can use this for a
beacon but i don't actually know where a
good idea to put the beacon is maybe
directly under my base just for the the
sake of it maybe i don't really know
maybe we'll leave that for another time
but for now i think we've done a huge
amount of work we got jack skelebone
back we have got ourselves loads of
progress in the base we've got ourselves
a water elevator we've got a really nice
coral reef aquarium around the edge
admittedly we've only got a handful of
fish in there but i'm sure that'll
change over time we have a really messy
base with all of this stuff just strewn
around everywhere i really gotta saw
this like each one has just junk
everywhere i'm sure if i organize this i
actually have a decent amount of things
but look at
the unorganization of this is really
starting to hurt
so i i need some sort of system maybe
this layer here can be my storage area
where i keep things and then up there
are more of the mechanical farming type
things who knows but this is going
really really well and i'm very happy
with it and i think for next episode i'm
gonna work on the rest of the base and
before we sign off this episode
i want to go and check if anyone has
bought the skeleton horses because
they've been up for sale for over a day
now and maybe just maybe someone spent
the money on them and
all three are still here
all three are still here no change
so as soon as somebody
buys one of these horses
they get the prize
inside
all right that's it for me everyone
thank you very much for watching i hope
you enjoyed this episode of hermitcraft
and i'll see you in the next one bye
mumbo jumbo you are afk
i'm gonna take that mustache away
mumbo mumbo mumbo afk
soon
you